Guide to the George A. Lindbeck Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
George A. Lindbeck Papers
1912-2007
1937-2001
RG 172
Yale University Divinity School Library
38.5
(92 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, notes, course-related material, and collected material document the life and work of George Lindbeck, noted Yale theologian. The collection is a rich source of information about Lutheran-Roman Catholic dialogue and Vatican II. Lindbeck, the Pitkin Professor Emeritus of Historical Theology, served on the faculty of Yale Divinity School and the Yale University Religious Studies department after graduating from the Divinity School in 1946 and receiving his Ph.D. from Yale in 1955. He is the author of six books, including The Nature of Doctrine: Religion and Theology in a Postliberal Age and Challenge and Response: A Protestant Perspective on the Vatican Council. Lindbeck's many awards include several honorary degrees and a Guggenheim Fellowship. He was a delegate to the second Vatican Council in Rome in the 1960s and has long been active in ecumenical dialogue, particularly between the Lutheran and Roman Catholic Churches. Lindbeck's "Report on Ecclesiastically Independent Theological Education" released by the Rockefeller Foundation in 1976 was also a notable contribution.
Lindbeck, George A.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of George A. Lindbeck
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers
Biographical / Historical
1923 George A. Lindbeck born in China on March 10, son of Lutheran missionaries.
1943 Received B.A. from Gustavus Adolphus College in Minnesota.
1944 Studied at Augustana Theological Seminary.
1946 Received M.Div. from Yale Divinity School.
1951 Completed two years of study, partially at the Pontifical Institute of Medieval Studies in Toronto, and partially at University of Paris (Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes).
1951 Named an Instructor at Yale.
1955 Received his Ph.D. from Yale University; named Assistant Professor at Yale.
1959 Completed Morse Research Fellowship from Yale in Tubingen, Germany.
1964 Completed two years as Delegated Observer of the Vatican Council in Rome.
1966 Named Associate Professor at Yale.
1966 Received honorary degrees from Notre Dame University and Augustana College.
1966 Published Challenge and Response: A Protestant Perspective on the Vatican Council.
1970 Published The Future of Roman Catholic Theology: Vatican II, Catalyst for Change.
1972 Fellow at the Center of Cultural and Ecumenical Research, St. John's University at Wolfson College.
1976 Fellow at Cambridge University, England.
1976 Release of Rockefeller Foundation "Report on Ecclesiastically Independent Theological Education."
1979 Fellow at the Tantur Ecumenical Institute, outside of Jerusalem.
1980 Received honorary degree from University of Munich, Germany.
1982 Named Pitkin Professor of Historical Theology at Yale.
1983 Received honorary degree from Upsala College.
1984 Published The Nature of Doctrine: Religion and Theology in a Postliberal Age.
1988 Received honorary degree from Gustavus Adolphus College.
1989 Held Guggenheim Fellowship.
1989 Visiting Professor of Ecumenics at the Gregorian University in Rome.
1993 Professor Emeritus
1997 Received honorary degrees from Jesuit School of Theology at Berkeley and Virginia Theological Seminary
1998 Received Wilbur Lucius Cross Medal by Yale Graduate School Alumni Association
2000 Received Paul Wattson Christian Unity Award from Franciscan Friars of the Atonement and honorary degree from Wartburg Seminary
2001 Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences
Scope and Contents
These papers document in a thorough way Lindbeck's work as a student, professor, and participant in ecumenical dialogue - his writings, lectures, courses taught at Yale, ecumenical activities, and work related to theological education. There is considerable overlap between the various series and sub-series described below.
The Correspondence of Series I dates from 1937 to 1996 and is primarily related to Lindbeck's academic and ecumenical work, rather than personal in nature. The series is organized chronologically, with undated letters at the end. The first sub-series of Series II, Writings, contains writings from Lindbeck's student days. The second part of Series II contains articles and reviews arranged according to the various topics of interest to Lindbeck. Series III, Material related to The Nature of Doctrine, contains response to the book by others, and Lindbeck's responses to the responses. Series IV, Notes, is grouped in broad topical categories. Series V, Course-Related Materials, documents Lindbeck's teaching activity at Yale. The material is organized by class number, with classes without a given number organized alphabetically. Series VI, Conferences/Lectures, contains drafts and finished products for Lindbeck's many speaking and conference engagements. The materials are arranged chronologically, with undated material arranged alphabetically by title. Series VII, Collected Materials: Theological Education, is organized into topics which are alphabetically ordered. Series VIII, Collected Materials: Ecumenism, is broken into subsections, including Lutheran, Roman Catholic, and Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogues. Within these subsections, materials are organized by topics which are alphabetically ordered. Series IX, Collected Materials: General, is organized by topics which are alphabetically ordered. Series X, Personal Items and Memorabilia, is organized by topics which are alphabetically ordered. An eleventh series, Addendum, was added in 2011 but with the receipt of additional documentation in 2014, the material from the Addendum series has now been integrated as subseries of the original series structure in order to provide better access.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1912-2007, n.d.
II. Writings, 1941-2006, n.d.
III. Materials related to The Nature of Doctrine, 1976-1988, n.d.
IV. Notes, 1965-1999, n.d.
V. Course-related Materials, 1952-1994, n.d.
VI. Conferences/Lectures, 1942-2006, n.d.
VII. Collected Materials: Theological Education, 1958-1992, n.d.
VIII. Collected Materials: Ecumenism, 1958-1992, n.d.
IX. Collected Materials: General, 1959-1992, n.d.
X. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1940-2004, n.d.
Theology -- Methodology -- History; Educators; Lindbeck, George A.
- Correspondence, 1912-2007, n.d.; Series I
  - Chronological sequence
    - To/from Relatives, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Friends; re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Christian Century ), 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Relatives; Friends (esp. seminarians), 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Incl. re: Theological Discussion; re: Loyang Mission Station Report, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Council of 13 (or Yale Correspondence Group); re: Ecumenism (incl. Bishop Oxnam); Stepney Methodist Church, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letter to Le Semeur; re: Fulbright (Paris), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Incl. re: Paris, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Re: Teaching Positions (Fr. Smith), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Relatives; Friends, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Re: Ordination; re: Kent Fellowship, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Friends, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Relatives, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Friends (esp. poetry); re: Editing/Publishing, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Colleagues, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Re: Ecumenism, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Re: Theological Education, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Federation (LWF) and World Council of Churches (WCC)); Theological Discussion Group, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - To wife from Strasbourg, 1962 Aug (Box 56, Folder 1315)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II), 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research); re: Lonergan, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Vatican II and Lutheran World Federation), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Re: Lutheranism; re: Editing/Publishing, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue and World Council of Chruches); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Una Sancta, ed. Richard Neuhaus), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Schillebeeckx; re: Ecumenism (esp. National Council of Churches and World Council of Churches); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Una Sancta, Neuhaus), 1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research (IER) and Lutheran World Federation:Inter-Confessional Research); re: Editing/Publishing, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Re: Reu Memorial Lectures; re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Westminster Press), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. WCC); re: Theological Education; re: Editing/Publishing, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Fortress Press, ed. Helmut Lehmann, and Una Sancta, Neuhaus), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Christian Century, and Una Sancta, Neuhaus); re: Ecumenism (esp. World Council of Churches); re: Singapore Trip, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran-Roman Catholic Dialogue); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Journal of Ecumenical Studies and Una Sancta, Neuhaus), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Federation and Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research and National Council of Churches of Christ); re: Missionary Conference, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Re: Edting/Publishing (esp. Journal of Ecumenical Studies and Fortress), 1969 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Journal of Ecumenical Studies and Fortress), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Encyclopedia Britannica); re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Federation and Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Journal of Ecumenical Studies, and Institute of Judaeo-Christian Studies, and Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Federation, and World Council of Churches), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Journal of Ecumenical Studies, and Institute for Ecumenical and Cultural Research), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. World Council of Churches); re: Theological Education (esp. Rockefeller Foundation- Michael Novak, and the Seven Theological Schools), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. National Council of the Churches of Christ); re: Theological Education (esp. the Seven Theological Schools, and Rockefeller Foundation-Michael Novak, and the Association of Theological Schools (ATS)), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran Church in America); re: Theological Education (esp.Rockefeller Foundation), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Re: Theological Education (esp. Graduate Theological Union (GTU), and the Association of Theological Schools, and Rockefeller Foundation, and the Seven Theological School), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research); re: Appointment of Faculty, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Lutheran Churches in America); re: Theological Education (esp. Rockefeller Foundation), 1977 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran Churches in America, and re: Augsburg Confession), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Ministries, and Institute for Ecumenical Research); re: Theological Education (esp. Catholic Theological Society of America); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Fortress Press, ed. Cooperrider), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran Presidents/Catholic Bishops Meeting, and Lutheran World Federation, and Institute for Ecumenical Research, and re: Augsburg Confession), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Ministries, and Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Lutheran World Federation, and Lutheran Churches in America), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Ministries, and Institute for Ecumenical Research), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Lutheran World Federation, and Lutheran Churches in America); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. SCM Press Ltd., ed. John Bowden), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran World Federation, and Institute for Ecumenical Research); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Pickwick Publications, ed. Dikran Hadidian), 1983 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Re: Ecumenism (Center on Religion an d Society, and Lutheran Council, and Journal of Ecumenical Studies ), 1984 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Lutheran World Ministries, and Lutheran Churches in America), 1985 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Re: Theological Education (esp. American Theological Society), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Re: Theological Education (esp. Boston Theological Institute), 1987 (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Center on Religion and Society); re: Editing/Publishing (esp. Marshall-Pickering, ed. Paul Avis), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Letter from Andrew Walls re. Karl Ludvig Reichelt, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 1312)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute for Ecumenical Research, and Religion and Society Institute, and Institute on Religion and Public Life), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute on Religion and Public Life), 1990 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Institute on Religion and Public Life), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - Marvin Pope, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - Re: Theological Education (esp. Center for Catholic and Evangelical Theology), 1992 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Journal of Ecumenical Studies ); re: Theological Education (esp. Rockefeller Foundation) (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Curia Generalizia), nd (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Re: Judaism (esp. with Institute of Judaeo-Christian Studies; Lutheran Church in America), nd (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Re: Nature of Doctrine, nd (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Re: Ecumenism (esp. Lutheran Churches in America, and Institute of Ecumenical and Cultural Research, and World Council of Churches); re: Theological Education (esp. Rockefeller Foundation), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Addendum: by sender or recipient
    - Ahlstrom-Attridge, 1969-2002 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Badham-Butcher, 1971-2002 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Cahoy-Cunningham, 1972-2000 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Dager-Dustin, 1983-1997 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Echols-Evangelista, 1978-1996 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Fackre-Fry, 1979-1997 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Gábor-Gustafason, 1972-1998 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Haddock-Hyers, 1981-2003 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Isaksen-Jordon, 1982-1996 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Kampschneider-Kvam, 1981-1999 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Lancaster-Lazareth, 1978-1997 (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Maas-Murphy, 1978-1999 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Namstad-Outka, 1979-1999 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Pantano-Price, 1968-1998 (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Radner-Ryan, 1982-2000 (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Saboe-Schattauer, 1979-1996 (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Schanderaff-Swidler, 1982-2007 (Box 58, Folder 17)
    - Taitt-Vikner, 1985-1999 (Box 58, Folder 18)
    - Wabash-Zhong, 1970-1999 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - No last names, 1966-1999 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Family, 1944-1998 (Box 59, Folder 21-22)
    - Family - re. China trip, 1997 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Family - letters of J. W. Lindbeck (father of G. L.), 1912-1971 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Family - Violet Lindbeck (wife of G. L.), 1963-1964 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - Family - Kris Lindbeck (daughter of G. L.), 1979-1993 (Box 59, Folder 26)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript, 1985-2000 (Box 59, Folder 27)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript - HarperCollins, 1996-1998 (Box 60, Folder 28)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript - Lindbeck memorandum, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 29)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript - Calhoun family, 1998 (Box 60, Folder 30)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript - WIPF & Stock, 2004-2007 (Box 60, Folder 31)
    - Re. Calhoun manuscript, 2003-2007 (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Yale Divinity School, 1984-1995 (Box 60, Folder 32)
    - Addendum: incl. McClymond, Meeks,Tracy (Box 91, Folder 8)
- Writings, 1941-2006, n.d.; Series II
  - Student
    - Book Reviews
      - Notes on Borsodi's Prosperity and Security, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 75)
      - On God and Immorality by Frederic Fitch, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 76)
      - The Nature and Destiny of Man by Niebuhr, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 77)
      - Review of Betrand Russell's Construction of the External World by Charles Fritz, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 78)
      - How to Read a Book by Adler, nd (Box 7, Folder 79)
      - Israel: Albright, Archaeology and Religion of Israel; Olmstead, History of Palestine and Syraia (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - A Faith for these Times by Conrad Bergendoff (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - Light from the Ancient East by Deissmann, nd (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Our Chief Business as a Church by S.C. Eastvold, nd (Box 7, Folder 83)
      - De Principiis Non Disputandum? An Essay on the Meaning and the Limits of Justification by Herbert Feigl (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - The Education of Henry Adams, nd (Box 7, Folder 85)
      - Expansion of Christianity V.1 by Harnack, nd (Box 7, Folder 86)
      - Psychology of Religion by Pratt, nd (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - The Birth of Gratitude by A.N. Ragness, nd (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - The Mystery of the Kingdom of God by A. Schweitzer, nd (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Thunder Rock (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Articles/Essays
      - "The Nevius Method and China Missions", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - "The Psychology of Religious Revivals", 1941 (Box 7, Folder 92)
      - "Mind, the Unknown", 1942 (Box 7, Folder 93)
      - "The Jesuit Missions of Paraguay", 1942 (Box 7, Folder 94)
      - "The Resurrected Deity in East and West", 1942 (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - "Matthew", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 96)
      - "The Epistles of the Captivity", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - "The Pastorial Epistles: I and II Timothy, Titus", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - "Commentary on Luke 16:1-9", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 99)
      - "Catholic Epistles: I and II Peter, Hebrews, James, Jude", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 100)
      - "Some Aspects of Thomistic Philosophy", 1944 (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - "The Theory of Knowledge of St. Thomas Aquinas", 1944-45 (Box 7, Folder 102)
      - "Reason in Brunner and Przywara", 1945 (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - "Report on the National Association of Manufacturer's Committee on Cooperation with the Churches", 1945 (Box 56, Folder 1314)
      - "Report on Causality as Will", 1946 (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - "Analogy", 1946 (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - "Schleiermacher's Doctrine of Sin", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 107)
      - "Some Reflections on Certainty in Thomistic Natural Theology: with Special Reference to Garrigou-La Grange's Work: God: His Existence and Nature", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 108)
      - "Was Kierkegaard a Lutheran?", 1947 (Box 7, Folder 109)
      - Draft of Dissertation Later Abandoned, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 110)
      - "Changes in Roman Catholic Attitudes to Protestantism", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 111)
      - "Protestantism in America", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 112)
      - "Thomism as Barrier and Bridge between the Confessions", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 113)
      - Dissertation:" Is Duns Scotus an Essentialist?", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 114)
      - Dissertation: "Is Duns Scotus an Essentialist?", 1955 (Box 8, Folder 115)
      - "Aristotle and the Theory of Relations" (Box 8, Folder 116)
      - "The Beginning of German Aggression", nd (Box 8, Folder 117)
      - "A Case Study of a Prejudice: An Experiment in Objective Introspection", nd (Box 8, Folder 118)
      - "The Character of John Woolman as Revealed in His Journal", nd (Box 8, Folder 119)
      - "The Church's Failure", nd (Box 8, Folder 120)
      - "Commentary on Mark VII: 24-29", nd (Box 8, Folder 121)
      - Devotional Literature Readings, nd (Box 8, Folder 122)
      - The Dial, nd (Box 8, Folder 123)
      - Education, nd (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - "A Geological Itinerary: Points of Interest on hte Northern Pacific Route", nd (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - Homiletics, nd (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - "Ideas of Relations", nd (Box 8, Folder 127)
      - "The Importance of Study", nd (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Medieval Theology, nd (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Newspaper Clippings, nd (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Notes on the Epistle of James, nd (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - "On English Sang-Froid", nd (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - "The Philosophical Approach of St. Thomas to Beatitude and Contemplation" (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - "Plotinus: An Apologetic", nd (Box 8, Folder 134)
      - Reading Report Old Testament Introduction, nd (Box 8, Folder 135)
      - Sermon Critiques, nd (Box 8, Folder 136)
      - "A Sketch of Lutheran Missions", nd (Box 8, Folder 137)
      - "The Social and Political Background of the Nicene Council" (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - Statement of My General Interest in College, nd (Box 8, Folder 139)
      - "The Synoptic Problem and Mark" (Box 8, Folder 140)
      - "Ulphilas and Gothic Missions" (Box 9, Folder 141)
      - "What is Substance?", nd (Box 9, Folder 142)
  - Bibliographies
    - Bibliographie von George A. Lindbecke; Publications of George A. Lindbeck, 1999; 1964 (Box 9, Folder 143)
  - Introductions
    - Theological Colloquium, Yale, Farrer as Speaker, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - Introduction to Lecture by Edward Schillebreeckx, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 145)
  - Articles: Ecumenism
    - General
      - "The New Vision of the World and the Ecumenical Revolution" in Religious Education, v.LXII n.2, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 146)
      - "The Present Ecumenical and Church Situation in West Malaysia and Singapore" in The South East Asia Journal of Theology, v.11, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 147)
      - "Ecumenism and World Mission: Foundations, Principles, and Policies" in Literature Survey: A Review of Recent Theological Publications, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 148)
      - "The Sectarian Future of the Church", 1970 (Box 9, Folder 149)
      - By Duchaine, Lindbeck, McDonnell, and Quanbeck "Ministry in the Universal Church" (draft), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 150)
      - "Creed and Confession" in Encyclopaedia Britannica, 15th ed., 1974 (Box 9, Folder 151)
      - "Creed and Confession" in Encyclopaedia Britannica, 15th ed., 1974 (Box 9, Folder 152)
      - "Election, Christian Apostasy and the Holocaust"; "Mission in the Holy Land", nd; 1979 (Box 9, Folder 153)
      - "The Ecumenical Import of Gaudium et Spes", nd (Box 9, Folder 154)
      - "Ecumenism and the Future of Belief" in Una Sancta, v. 25 n.3 (Box 9, Folder 155)
      - "Issue: The Divided Church" in Call to Global Mission Background Papers (unpublished) (Box 9, Folder 156)
      - Preface to a Book of Catholic Scholarship on Luther, nd (Box 9, Folder 157)
      - "A Protestant View of the Ecclesiological Status of the Roman Catholic Church" in Journal of Ecumenical Studies, v.1 n.2, nd (Box 9, Folder 158)
      - Response to Vischer Report in World Council of Churches; "Zur Methode und Rezeption Interkonfessioneller Dialoge" by Vischer (Box 9, Folder 159)